[Music]
let's build a centered stack of squares
consisting of one square in the top row
three squares in the second row five
squares in the third row and so on
adding the odd numbers in each
consecutive row
the resulting stack is a representation
of the sum of the first n odd numbers
but we can rotate this stack creating
four total copies and when we do that
the resulting shape is a perfect square
[Music]
the area of the resulting 2n by 2n
square is just 2n times 2n which
simplifies to 4 times n squared
[Music]
therefore
four times the sum of the first n odd
numbers is equal to four times n squared
if we divide both sides by four we see
that the sum of the first n odd integers
is equal to n squared
you